TYLER SIMEONE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

in /in/tylersimeone

7 /tyler-simeone



ABOUT ME

I am a young, driven and goal-oriented student born in New York, but raised in Nashville, TN. When I'm not programming I enjoy spending time outdoors or learning new things that interest me. I am passionate about technology, innovation and growth.

I became aware of programming at a young age as my dad has been a programmer since the '80s. However, it wasn't until I took an online course that I realized programming was something that I would really enjoy doing as a career. I love working in teams and solving challenging problems to achieve goals.

MTB CONNECT

- Web Application that allows users to search mountain bike trails by zip code and build a network of mountain biking friends that ride similar trails.
- I built this front-end app in three
 weeks using React.js with React State
 and React Hooks for displaying data
 and handling the user interface. CSS
 and Material UI for styling. As well as
 JSON Server with fetch requests for
 data storage and manipulation.
- https://github.com/tylersimeone/MTB-Connect

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Full-stack Web Development

Columbia State Community College Associate of Science Degree

SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Software Developer

Nashville Software School

AUG 2019 - PRESENT

Intensive full-time, full-stack software development course with an emphasis on individual and team-based projects.

Three months of remote learning and group project experience.

TECH STACK:

- Built single page front-end and full-stack web applications using JavaScript, React, Python, Django, SQL, HTML and CSS
- Utilized Git and GitHub for version control and issue tracking
- Utilized React State, Hooks, and Props to render data to the page and handle the user interface
- Utilized Django REST framework to build APIs for full-stack applications

REACT NUTSHELL - (Group Project)

- Multi-functional site built with a team of four that features news articles, local events, restaurants, and task lists
- Individually responsible for building React task components and API calls that allow the user to perform CRUD operations on their task list using JavaScript, React.js, Reactstrap and JSON Server
- https://github.com/nss-day-cohort-38/react-nutshell-pyroclastic-thunder-nerds

WORK EXPERIENCE

Franklin Water Store - Sales Associate

JUL 2018 - JUL 2019

Small business focused on producing and selling alkaline drinking water

• Developed a strong sense of teamwork and communication while working with a small team to help customers understand the benefits of alkaline water and water ionizing machines

Delivery Dudes - Delivery Driver

APR 2015 - MAY 2018

- Grew strengths in detail and focus while fulfilling customer orders remotely from the Delivery Dudes headquarters using a proprietary web app
- Delivery driver where I optimized regular delivery routes to achieve more efficient order fulfillment times and increase productivity and sales during my shift